so something that's really funny uh
every time I talk with you with supply
chain is that I show you all those
researches and then I see your name in
the research and like every time but
every time like uh I think we were
talking about um the Travis uh research
from of Travis c yeah and I was talking
to you about that you were like you know
that I'm on the paper and I was like
you're that Justin
okay
[Music]
[Applause]
D hey everyone this is technog geek here
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
our latest sponsor project Discovery now
project Discovery makes a lot of tools
that you probably know of or have even
used uh one of the them is nuclei and
the latest release of nuclei is version
3.2 now 3.2 comes with a lot of really
awesome new features um two that I
really wanted to highlight here for you
are the authenticated scanning and the
advanced fuzzing support now for
authenticated scanning it used to be
that you would have to do all your
nuclei scanning against unauthenticated
end points or you'd have to add your
cookies manually all that kind of messy
no more it's all automatic you can use
existing login templates to
automatically log in to your application
and then you can run all your existing
nuclei templates against an
authenticated part of the application
now to really increase your coverage uh
the other that I mentioned is Advanced
fuzzing support now nuclea had added way
back in version 2.8 the ability to fuzz
different things but now they've
expanded this comprehensively across the
board so not only can you fuzz in the
normal spots but you can fuzz within
headers you can fuzz within cookies you
can fuzz within specific parts of the
body whether that's in j
or XML or form data and so many more
things so if you want to learn more
about what came in nuclei 3.2 go ahead
and check out the the release blog post
over at nu.
gpod that's
nx. podcast thanks every time every time
before I start a podcast I just I start
you know by jumping I just get some get
some jumps out right before we go so
it's hilarious to see it maybe I need to
do it on on camera um all right Lupin
welcome back to the Pod man you're a
second time guest we also had you here
on episode 37 that one was live from
Japan which is pretty freaking cool um
now we're live from friends so that's
also great there we go it's it's another
location um but yeah man excited excited
to have you back on and um I think it's
very timely with all the stuff you've
been releasing lately um just as right
before we're recording this episode you
who just released a blog post um
outlining of vulnerability in uh npm uh
which was crazy and we'll talk about
that uh but today the focus of today's
episode is going to be on um supply
chain attacks and dependency confusion
which you are an expert on um so maybe
we could just go ahead and start off
with give me a little bit about how you
got into that space and uh tell me about
deppy the the tool the amazing tool
you've made uh to secure supply chain
stuff yeah definitely
um so how I get into that space I think
like everybody has um it's when Alex Bon
released his book post on the benic
confusion and uh this was amazing at the
time I think I really love this
viability because it was disrupting
right it was another way of seeing
Scopes and we removed the domain
component component of a scope and we
are more talking about packages Supply
chains and all those buzzword that no
one really understand and I wanted to
understand
them uh so in 2021 uh I I I started like
creating this small bash script 50 lines
of bash and I was pulling JavaScript and
then exfiltrating all the the packages
from the JavaScript and trying to see if
we could the take over uh in the public
registry so the goal of dependency
confusion is that you have two ways of
uh of putting a package you you have the
private Factory and the public registry
right and so what berson like thought
was what if I just put the same package
like the same name but just an higher
version on the public registry which one
the artifactory will peck and uh that's
where the entire mess uh
started yeah and and now you know supply
chain stuff has become a whole I mean it
was really an underserved attack surface
I think uh you know prior to that whole
blog post and I I was rereading that
blog post in in preparation for this
podcast and it has 20,000 claps on
medium and and I'm like
whoa not 20,000 views not 20 20,000
people that have a freaking medium
account you know clapping um and I was
like wow okay this was a really big
thing and and I I um uh I was I was
working with him on the original um you
know vulnerability that occurred uh that
sort of uh spurred this whole thought
and so I was cited in the paper and I
remember when it came out and it got
really big a whole bunch of people that
like I knew from college are reaching
out to be like wait a second are you are
you that Justin gter and I'm like yeah
and I just I was really impressed by the
the reach of it but now I'm starting to
understand you know supply chain is a
whole whole Massive Attack um you know
attack surface um and there's lots of
different attacks that that can go along
in in supply chain stuff um not just
dependency confusion something that's
really funny uh time I talk with you
with supply chain is that I show you all
those researches and then I see your
name in the research and like every time
but every time like uh I think we were
talking about um the Travis uh research
from head of Travis c yeah and I was
talking to you about that you were like
you know that I'm on the paper and I was
like you're that Justin
okay yeah man you know it's I I think
that's just two really good examples of
being at the right place at the right
time and knowing the right people
because um you know the Travis C stuff
that was a really interesting period in
my in my bug Bounty development and and
um you know the work with that overflow
and and Corbin Leo and or Lan CEO as I
like to call him uh and and you know
that whole that whole era was really was
really fun and then the you know I just
kind of got pulled into that by the that
crew and then the same thing happened
you know with with Al with Alex I was
like okay uh let's hack on this this you
know PayPal Target for a live hacking
event and I just shared some code to
Alex and he was like oh wait a second
what if I totally hijacked that code and
I'm like whoa um but but but I think I
think there's before we get into like
all of the technical details of um
supply chain attacks and dependency
confusion and that sort of thing I think
there is a um I think there's some
groundwork we need to set here because
most of the time when bug bounty hunters
are are you know hacking we're focusing
on the web scope and this is really not
um you know in some ways it's tangental
to the web scope but um this is really
before all of this in the software
development life cycle um so so could
you give us an overview um and I and we
do have a little little graphic here
we'll put up at the screen uh um you
know uh for those people walk watching
on YouTube about sort of the the flow of
supply chain but um could you talk a
little bit about how applications are
built and how they're deployed and how
what kind of surface we have within that
environment um so the graph that you
mentioning is coming from the salsa
standard that is being constructed with
the op ssf Foundation uh primarily
founded by Google and by the Linux
foundation so uh those are like really
interesting people to work with and um
and so basically on the graph uh you see
that there is like three main attack
threads or attack surface uh there is
the source the build and uh the package
so let's say that the source is
everything related to the artif
factories and the Registries right so
for instance your jrog is your
artifactory and your registry will be
npm pip everything where you can set up
a public package right then you have uh
the build attack surface it's everything
where you are pulling from a source and
then you are uh building your artifact
so basically all your code your
dependencies uh at the moment where you
are the step before deploying it right
MH and then there there is the package
uh that you produce uh so once
everything is built uh you are
publishing the package again and the
package can come back as a dependency
for another build so that's basically
how um the Sasa standard is defining the
the attacks ofice of the entire supply
chain okay so so let me let me repeat
this back to make sure I've got it um
you know we've got the devs they're
writing the code you know they're in
their vs code doing their magic right
and then um they're committing that into
a GitHub repo right which is also I
imagine you know a part of the source
piece and um and you've also got that
Source um stored in in an internal
environment when we're talking about
these bigger you know tech companies are
stored um you know it can be in a local
version of of GitHub it can be in a
GitHub Enterprise uh you know
organization or whatever it could be on
the actual um GitHub cloud in just a
private organization um and then you've
also got these sort of um artifactory
well okay let me let me ask you this can
you define artifactory and registry for
us because I kind of get those two terms
um mixed up in my head a little bit
sometimes so uh for me an artifactory is
uh where you're going to publish all
your private artifacts or private uh
dependencies and uh it's where you are
basically pulling all the packages for
your internal
organization um so artifactory can be
jrog Google as their own artifactory
called the uh Google uh artifact
registry uh there is a code artifact for
AWS um basically it's often pulled from
cloud providers or there is like jrog
their own providers right um so those
packages are here to instrument and help
uh create a standard across your
organization for where you are putting
the packages and then uh there is the
Registries so basically an N Factory
will pull all the packages is from the
public Registries if it doesn't exist uh
on the internal artifactory so um it's
like a hub artifactory is like a hub for
all the different uh Registries and uh
it creates like some kind of bottleneck
uh for when you want to pull uh
dependencies uh and that's uh where it
becomes interesting because once you
have a central centralized piece uh of
your supply chain you can uh really uh
log money
and uh and deploy application more
easily for your developers Okay Okay so
we've got the the artifactory that's
sort of like your local version of the
registry that's all for your private
packages and artifacts that are um
internal to your organization like maybe
your helper tools or some of the other
stuff um that are that are often used
within your organization maybe your like
UI components that sort of thing um
could go in there and then and then
you've got the registry which is like
public packages that are um being reused
by lot of different organizations and
are being shared um uh across the whole
sort of software development um industry
um okay and that's all all of that's a
part of source and then um we go into
the build area and then um from from
there we're building you know our
packages bundling everything together
and then we've got um the the pack so
that's where like our continuous
integration stuff comes in that's like
Travis CI that's um you know uh what is
the um
GitHub action G lines yeah exactly so
that's all that um lots of attack
vectors there as we know we we'll cover
those later and then finally we've got
the package that gets produced and that
package um can be reused by other um uh
components and that sort of brings us
back around to the beginning of the of
the lifestyle or life cycle again or at
least over to the build step where those
packages are being used in other in
other um artifacts and and being um sort
of nested like that is that accurate
yeah yeah exactly and um this attack
surface is one of the most interesting
uh because we've seen in the past uh few
months a lot of vulnerability in the CI
builds like um public repositories have
been here for years audited many many
times uh that yeah from one day to
another you manage to pull out all the
credentials because there is Cash on
GitHub like somehow uh you can do
something like that that and it's crazy
it's it's crazy and um basically this
attack surface why it's interesting
because you can uh run remote code uh
execution as a service um so here you
have a bit more Privileges and also
depending on who can run a pipelines uh
you are going to be exposed to different
kind of vulnerabilities for instance um
there is a lot of configuration when
every time you do a pull request to
contribute to a code base there is
pipelines to check your code and so
there is a remote Cod execution as a
service here which yeah which is super
interesting already yeah and and the
testing infrastructure I think for all
of these as well is can be sort of built
in as well so that's another piece of
this that that um there could be uh
vulnerabilities int introduced into and
then um so then taking this the full the
full step um you know after you you do
your build and you're in your um uh
continuous deployment continuous
integration flow that's when that code
is actually hitting prod ex and it's
getting pushed out into um into the web
apps that we normally think about as
we're hacking uh these these targets
yeah um exactly okay and and so what we
want to try to attack here is any piece
of that flow and um as a part of the
prep for this episode we've kind of gone
through here and let me see one two
three four five six seven roughly seven
um sort of ways that you can attack this
whole flow yeah that we had and I'm sure
we'll come up with more as we start
talking definitely well I think I think
this this podcast would be brainstorming
more than anything yeah yeah as it
always ends up to be you know whenever
we chat Liv so um I'm looking forward to
that um so the first thing that I kind
of want to talk about uh where we can
sort of attack in this in this flow is
getting us our our scope what what kind
of things can we attack in this flow and
how do we identify the entities that we
can attack um and and for me I think
that looked it's a lot like identifying
these
packages um uh in in in repos um so so
what are the most I mean obviously you
know we can look at an organization's
GitHub repo but I imagine there's more
more ways to enumerate scope for that uh
can you give us a couple of those there
is so many so many ways uh so uh we have
all the traditional ways will uh package
I call that um aactor file I I don't
know if it's the literal term for that
but I I call it uh that so it's
everything like package.json Jame file
y.l requirements.txt uh you can find it
on the all the open source repositories
of your target but um here uh all the
packages tend to be uh public in general
uh you can find some private packages
because there is developers sometime
pushing their the internal source code
and it's always really funny and we're
going to talk a bit more about those
kind of techniques and how to find those
internal source code Expos uh but um
there is this traditional where you put
like open source right and then uh you
can go try uh to uh do some fuzzing on
uh on your target so there is a lot of
people exposing their uh web rout and
this is where a package Jason lives in
general and so you can enumerate them
and try to to First them get them back
and start your dependency analysis from
here that's interesting but the most
interesting techniques is when a
package.json file ends up in the front
end uh directly and that's something
that uh we talked a lot uh with the
people that are doing JS whizzle um and
they actually implemented uh a detection
for that inside JS whizzle wow cool yeah
uh where basically uh there is um in the
JavaScript somehow some libraries are
just taking the package that Json file
and uploading that in the front end as a
string or as an object um and so you can
just basically go in the JavaScript pull
all the strings uh in a way and then
just see the package that Jason no way
it's so funny and um and so that you can
do on minified uh JavaScript actually so
you don't need the do map file but if
you want to go a little bit further you
can pull the dot map uh file of the
JavaScript so basically um everything
that will help you to
reconstruct uh the source code and there
is two ways of checking packages here uh
there is um the sources like a do map
file is is a Json file so there is the
source key and there there is the source
code right and so in the source key you
can see all the names of uh the packages
so you just pull not modules and you'll
see some names and also web pack for
instance and you'll see then some
dependencies and so here you already
have all the dependencies that are
shipped in the the front end and that
you can also start analysis on wow okay
so so we've got obviously we're going to
be looking at um
the uh open source uh repos you know on
GitHub or on gitlab or whatever and
we're going to be um assessing those
thoroughly but also any any web app that
is out there you know so many of these
web apps are are using like webpack and
that sort of structure nowadays um and
so also inside of those the the
package.json file might be included um
and uh you know it could just be living
in the web rout as well so we always
want to hit those end points and I've
seen that time and time again you know
that that's one of the things that I
think is on my quick Hits list uh for
directory brute forcing is like making
sure that package checking that
package.json file um and there's like a
lock I think package-lock Json file as
well um that we can hit there one one
thing that I wanted to add here that I
think would also be a um a helpful piece
is um this whole concept of dumping the
git history and this was such an amazing
um I remember the moment that I learned
about this technique and this and this
technique was solidified in my head I
was at a live hacking event in London
with um Tom Nom Nom and he found just a
absolute Mega crit on the target uh
because he he downloaded all the open
source repositories and he ran this tool
that he built called get dump on it and
you can find it in his um I believe it's
in his actual in his DOT files uh repo
but essentially what it does is it takes
a a a repository and it uses Git You
Know git is version history to go
through and dump every file that's ever
existed into this massive txt file um
for that GitHub repo right okay and so
um one of the things that I I thought
would be pretty cool here is like uh if
they were using um certain packages in
the past or uh looking at the changes to
those package.json file over time um and
then maybe grabbing some of those um
packages that they're no longer using
but were using in the past might give
you an in into some of the dev machines
or machines that haven't been fully
updated to the latest version of that
open source repository um uh you know it
might be able to give you access to
those if they're still pulling from that
same from that same package.json file
yeah I think it's a super interesting
idea because uh we had some of our
clients that asked us hey uh on your
analysis we we going to talk about the
tool later but it's interesting just to
say that uh some people are like
maintaining um a repository with
different versions at the same time like
they're just branching all those
versions and so looking at one
repository on always the light latest
version of course you will find some
stuff but when you know that some
repositories are maintained across like
many different versions from one. X to
4.x here you can see all the different
teams and developers doing like working
on some different stuff and so they
asked us like to scan like every commit
ever uh on all the different branches
because uh they they know that from one
version to another then it's not the
same libraries that's a great point you
know and they they've got to go back and
say there's a bug found in an earlier
you know still supported version if
somebody's relying on that they've got
to go back and patch that version and
rebuild it and reship it right and so um
you know if you're able to inject into
that point whenever they need to redo
that again re rep it re-release that
version um then there's going to be a
problem something interesting is that uh
a lot of Registries do not allow you to
delete a version you can have like up to
24 hours to delete it but once it's live
it's live it means that if you find like
a dependency issue or a supply chain
issue you need to rebuild the package
and update uh the version so the minor
version and you will just update it but
if someone out coded the version to say
I just want this specific version they
will still be avable and there is a bug
that we're going to talk about it later
here where there is this exact same
problem yeah no that that's that's
really pivotal and and it really speaks
to the the depth and breadth of the
supply chain problem because um there
there are so many people that are like
all right listen I don't want to deal
with dependency hell you know I don't
want to deal with like all of this
garbage that that uh you know I got to
reinstall this version and then this
version becomes you know incompatible
with that version I don't want to deal
with all that so I just lock my my um
you know script or my program or
whatever to the specific version so it
always functions exactly how I I
anticipate that it will um but the
problem with that is that dependencies
can change over time as well you know
and and some of the pieces that have
have um you know that that version might
have been built upon uh could introduce
vulnerability or um another place we're
thinking about going with this or we're
definitely going to go with with this
chat as well is like what happens when
static resources get deleted um out of
these packages and uh what kind of Havoc
that can bring um so definitely want to
go there we we'll definitely get there
um but I do want to take a second uh and
talk about deppy um so you mentioned you
know scanning across all of these
different versions of the of the um of
the packages uh can you talk a little
bit about how you've architected
did De because I keep on wanting to ask
you about tools for this because I'm
like am I going to go do this manually
but then but then but then I'm like oh
wait he is the author of the talk so
yeah um I need to tell you a bit more
about the the story of De because I
think like this you really understand
more about the architecture uh so
basically as I say in 2021 I did this uh
small bash script and I was
collaborating a lot with Snorlax at the
time and we were like always targeting
the same uh company and our goal was to
find like every kind of viabilities on
that company like every Buck type we
wanted it right uh so that was like a
fun that's a great goal let's just pause
for a second and appreciate that goal
all right go ahead go ahead go ahead no
that was a fun game um and so uh we were
on the dependency confusion route that I
did this bash script that was just
pulling Javascript file checking the the
packages and on the first run of my 59 B
script we managed to find the the pens
conf Fusion we claimed the package and
at the time there wasn't any Banning of
the packages and so uh it lived for one
week and then we got hit and uh we
managed to to have a remot code
execution trigger so that was like the
first ever hit of Dei uh which was a
refund at the time it wasn't called that
it was just called like hey the pic
fusion.
script Ronnie's little script yeah
exactly great and um and you know uh my
my my brother is um a backend developer
and one day after months of using that
kind of script I I I went to him and I
was like hey uh do you want to help me
like build uh the scrip but better
because at one point I I you know I'm
not a software developer and uh he told
me
no he told me no I don't care and I'm
like let's do just do a proof concept
really quickly and then uh I came back
with some bounties and I just paypaled
him uh some bounties and he was like now
we're talking what the heck is happening
you know he's not like in the security
field so it was interesting to see like
developers versus
security um and so I tricked him into
building de oh my gosh that's great yeah
uh at the time it was like a small
project and then we moved into a company
and we don't really understand how that
happened uh but it's it still did
I can just see you with like wads of
cash just come here come here write the
code you can do it I I think it was more
like the technical challenge of a lot of
stuff that that that we were doing but
yeah bun is really helped to in the
argument at least to get his attention
right yeah exactly yeah um but but yeah
we we walked a lot and we had like a so
many different architectures at the time
uh we weren't weren't even saving
packages in our database uh because we
wanted it to be the most lightweight
possible we had like this script
architecture in mind but then it moved
to a full back end and now to an entire
uh ecosystem architecture with many
microservices uh to optimize everything
um so yeah we have a lot of different uh
modules and our methodology is a simple
we have like a crazy idea and we're like
we need to confirm this idea so we are
going to build a module
that we go in development mode research
mode of depi and just spread uh this
Theory across all the Scopes uh that
that we have right and here we are going
to collect all the information of all
the odd and agnostic results that we
have like stuff that aren't uh in the
scope of our hypothesis right we do an
hypothesis we will find that and
everything that is not inside this scope
we are going to dig it and and that's
where we find a lot of zero days and new
dependency confusion and more than depy
confusion supply chain
issues so w that's how that's an amazing
structure man I love
that yeah definitely and that's how uh
we we had it in mind uh dep is really a
tool to help for research uh on on like
the first thing it was built for was for
research and then it became a tool for
companies uh to just take the modules
that they are interested in and uh scan
them internally um so basically we're
going to pull all the the artif
factories file uh all the build files
and then we're going to to scam for any
supply chain uh issues in depth
really okay gotcha and just before uh I
know we're going to get inundated with
comments if I don't say this um deppy is
not an open source tool it is a software
as of service and is Enterprise focused
um and so there's no worry where you can
go download this tool right now this is
a uh this is a uh a startup that that
Ronnie is running um so I'm just GNA put
that out there yeah um that being said
uh you know you have a ton of experience
architecting and developing this tool
for um detecting supply chain uh attacks
and I I'm I'm curious where the 8020 is
in this in this Arena I I I'm curious
where um what are the what are the 20
thing 20% of things you know of the
whole that we can do as bug bounty
hunters uh to to get 80% of the results
80% of the bugs um where where's most of
that meat living in this environment and
how can we code our own scripts
surrounding this yeah essentially what
I'm asking is give away your secret
sauce but you knew that before you came
onto the Pod you knew that I knew I knew
yeah um one thing that that is really
interesting is that um supply chain
detection make more sense to do it
internally inside the companies and
that's why we built uh the this tool to
be uh for like startup company focused
right because it make more sense to to
scan from the inside and to have the
entire list of dependencies and from
here start our research right uh now
that being said there is a lot of
exposure of uh of of dependencies and
that the the supply chain scope is
interesting because it's not like
traditional web app scope like it's not
tied to a domain uh and that's something
that is re bothering a lot in the backy
when you find vities that not tied to a
domain but supp chain is not tied to a
domain and so one package that can exist
out of scope on an autoscope domain can
still be impacting an inscope domain
because there is this entire supply
chain
build so uh once that you manage to
detect uh any dependency there is so
many stuff uh that you can look for as
we said uh you have uh the sources uh
you have uh the cicd build that you want
to try to exploit and then uh the there
is um what's happening in the package
but also how the package is being pulled
so all those areas is where I I guess
the 20% uh
hides we're going to we're going to need
to build that we're going to need to to
cut that down a little bit um but I
guess it makes more sense for us to go
through the list of what kind of attacks
there are possible first and then sort
of come back to that 8020 question so
yeah you be like continue noodling I'm
letting I'm letting my Southern uh
Southern vocabulary come out here keep
thinking on that while we're um while
we're going through these which ones
give you the most Bank for your buck and
then you know we'll we'll um talk about
that again after we've gone through the
whole list um so first one obviously
we've already discussed this a little
bit but it's dependency confusion and
essentially my my tldr of this one is um
there are ways to make uh to make
organizations download the incorrect
package from a registry right that
that's the kind of that's the kind of
way I I see it and that could be because
of um there being a uh a confusion
between the the version and the name
and or like um being able to to claim a
package that has been um uh I guess
abandoned or something like that or or
maybe one that doesn't even exist and
and it's trying to download it and it's
failing um uh and so that that's the one
where we sort of think about um that was
really popular with Alex peerson um and
the whole concept of that is pulling a
package down from um from a registry now
I had a couple questions surrounding
this one um
obviously there's this whole confusion
of like will will it pull from the local
artifactory or will it pull from the
registry right and the best way to do
that I imagine would be to just try it
but in order for you to try it you have
to get these payloads hosted on the
registry so you've got to go to npm or
whatever you got to sign up for a
package you've got to put some package
out there and here's the kicker that
package has to contain some code that
will somehow let you know that it's
being downloaded and run okay and
recently if I recall directly from our
conversations uh these various
Registries have been making that very
difficult um could you talk a little bit
about how we can host these packages
nowadays in such a way that we can test
responsibly and also um test effectually
uh to be able to figure out whether this
code is being run or not yeah definitely
um we we've done a lot of research uh on
that uh because um like the way that we
are building dep is that uh we are
actually finding vulnerabilities on
buges and everything that is being paid
will be implemented inside everything
that is not being paid is not
implemented right wow very high signal
yeah exactly and that's we want to
reduce false positives and like BS
vulnerability right uh but we had a lot
of push back from programs because uh we
we couldn't host uh a back door and not
only uh because Registries are Banning
you but also because there is a lot of
legal and ethical uh problems uh with it
because uh legally you don't know if the
your target is um an employee of the bti
program that you are hacking and so if
someone uh like call you and like hey
you have backed on my PC and I don't
know you what's happening it's going to
be really problematic so we had a lot of
push back from Traders and programs just
telling us hey break the
and uh and then we'll see and I'm like I
can't like in France I can't I know in
other countries you can in France I
can't so we did a lot of research on how
you can host uh packages publicly and
I'm I I'm seeing like a um like right
now you know how like uh truffle truffle
Seck does their like very like
dramatized videos that are just super
engaging I just see but I can't do that
here in France and now it cuts to like
you on a plane you know flying over to
like I don't know turkey or something
like that you know I love their videos
oh man it's so good so good okay so yeah
France has some some rules surrounding
that and I think even in the US I think
there's a little bit more of a um you
know we've got sort of a blanket which
is like if you're performing ethical
security research then you know there's
there's sort of an a caveat there and
that's not really strictly defined so
that makes a lot of people uncomfortable
but over the over the past um couple
years I've seen a lot of people push the
boundaries of what I would go for and
not sort of experience any consequences
so I I am starting to think that the US
is a little bit more liberal with this
um so but yeah we are trying to to do
the right thing and also because we are
not just you know bugy Hunters we are
also a company and so we need to to to
stay ethical uh and do things correctly
and so we did a lot of research and we
managed to find a technique in order to
host a back door on the public
Registries uh without um scanners or uh
or people that are not from the
organization to download the the package
uh how we did that is uh actually really
easy uh we created our own
registry and uh we we published uh a
package a normal uh package and then uh
on the public registry uh one of the
dependency is the URL of our
registry ah oh okay all right all right
and so what we do is that we send like
dummy packages uh like stuff just to to
to check and uh we say to to in our back
end those packages if they are being
pulled this is a scanner so we can serve
them a Bine package but if it's not a
scanner that is at a blacklist we can
just swap uh the the package on the Fly
and so they download a malicious version
where we exfiltrate content and that's
how we did it we basically have like at
this uh URL that is you know normal
regular to have another registry and
then we check on the registry if this is
a scanner or if it is not and so we are
swapping on the fly when you download uh
the package very cool very cool okay so
but that requires a lot of
infrastructure i' imagine to set up
register have all that in place so all
right well there there are some barriers
to entry there for that one um if if you
were a bug Bounty Hunter you know going
after this did didn't have all of this
set up in place any any tips or tricks
for them or is pretty much at this point
they've kind of nailed it down to the
point where it's like okay well if
you're not doing this whole um
independent registry with the hot
swapping of the packages thing then
you're kind of in trouble yeah we are in
trouble because um it has become a cat
and mouse uh game why because Registries
do not have any ways to discriminate if
you're a m actor or Bug Hunter and so
they don't they don't care about your
Bounty right they don't care about you
succeeding your attack and helping
people what else is new yeah they just
don't want any back door inside the
registry which is totally normal right
that makes sense and so uh yeah this is
a cat and mouse game and you need to do
this kind of OD swap um but us because
we we wanted to do the e schol thing we
went a bit further and now we are
actually asking companies to provide
their IP ranges and so we can just uh do
an allow list and we are sure that no
one that is not from this allow list uh
will uh will run our back door um and
that's how we manag to stay
ethical uh while still managing to
exploit dependency confusion
properly wow man I don't know I would
have gone to that the that length that's
uh that's pretty thorough but I guess I
mean you got to have all of your bases
covered when you're when you're a
startup um so you know that makes a lot
of sense and it seems like you guys have
I mean just thinking about it from a
technical perspective you've taken it
really seriously and taken it about as
far as you possibly can um you know to
ensure that you're that no other um
parties are being affected and it's also
not like it's also not like you're
dropping malware on the you know on the
target as soon as as soon as they
download it so I I think even just you
know maybe exfiltrating the path and the
host name and you know some stuff like
that it's not even that malicious for a
normal user um but on top of that you
you have built in all these protections
so um I think that's a really a really
responsible way of going after it a
little I'm a little sad to say though
that uh that that the um there's not a
really an easy way to address this from
a bug bounty hunters perspective I I
I've seen um a research from a company
called Supply shark uh where what they
did is that um they did something very
similar with a G up repo and where
basically for the first week uh there
will be a lot of scanners and then they
swap uh in the gab repo after the first
week so you need to wait for a week
where you don't know if you are going to
actually maybe do a denial of service on
your Target because we are swapping
packages so maybe there is some
pipelines that will just crash and you
will have no way to know that but at the
same time you will avoid the scanners
and you can make a a back door leave on
the public registry uh I do not prefer
this technique I think o swapping is
better for because for all the eal
implication that we have behind but if
really someone wants to park dep pens
confusion really easily uh doing that
trick with the GitHub from soly Shar we
we do the trick yeah definitely that
that that's a good a good caveat maybe a
good work around for that um good to
know and and so now I guess when you're
actually doing your exfiltration um when
you've hot swapped your package in now
you're running your quote unquote
malicious very very benign malicious
code um uh how are you excal trting are
you doing it over HTP or are you doing
it over DNS like the original dependency
confusion post outline yeah but for now
we are doing uh over HTTP uh but it can
be done to to DNS without any problem
and I think it's better to do it uh to
DNS because there will be a lot of um
egress and firewalls that will block you
uh from xuting to http but the truth is
uh if you manage to pull our registry uh
you can also ping it back so I sure sure
so I I I don't that's why we didn't do
the DNS uh path because once you you
pull from the the public registry uh
that that's it but this is interesting
when the artifactory is actually pulling
your package and so the artifactory has
the right to go through the internet but
not uh your your machine your end your
end level machine okay that makes sense
so it's also sort of like a okay you've
got this um artifactory server that's
reaching out and then dropping it back
down to the user so it's sort of like
that same you know it's one of the
things I like about DNS as an
exfiltration method is like the whole
recursive nature of it right like you
know I'll just send out my payload and
that's going to get you know bumped from
one DNS server to another DNS server to
another DNS server to another D and then
it's going to land on my on my machine
and it it allows you to exfiltrate out
of really you know wonky scenarios but
you do at least have one layer of that
with these sort of artifactory based
things because you've got that
artifactory in between you and the end
user um and the artifactory of course is
going to have much more uh liberal
egress rules um so so that's that that's
cool I'm wondering if there's any room
for ACC combin of the both where it's
like okay um we can do a a sort of
benign DNS call back just like ah this
popped and then also you know have the
registry run yeah I I think I think
definitely there is a lot of exitation
techniques that possible um I don't
think that in a backy situation or even
us as a company we we need those uh
because if you manage to pull one
package uh like the the the chances are
really slim that you went through an
artifactory that has the rights but your
computer do not have the the right so
it's possible there a lot of companies
are setting up like that but I haven't
have that issue that that often but also
but also you wouldn't see that issue if
you did have it though that's that's
true there is some truth here but U
again on the ethical thing uh if if you
exate to DNS there is a lot of as you
say DNS server that can see what you are
exfiltrating and and and so I do it over
https uh just to have this kind of layer
encryption because you know I'm paranoid
with that kind of stuff no no I couldn't
tell um that's great man that's awesome
you get you're really checking all your
boxes and um dotting all your eyes and
crossing your tees there so I think
that's that's really good um so let's so
that's the basic sort of um dependency
confusion stuff and I'm sure that
there's a lot of nuance to that you know
in various systems you know for nuances
for for pip for npm and that sort of
thing but let's let's talk about a more
a broader range um or a more a bigger
concept when it comes to supply chain
which is maintainer attacks and the
whole concept behind this um for those
not familiar with it is that you know
each one of these re repositories that
we're trusting uh these packages that
we're trusting with our our code flow um
are maintained by a bunch of unpaid
open- Source you know maintainers that
just love the community um and do it
because of that but um because they're
not getting paid because it's not their
actually their responsibility or any
skin off their back sometimes they may
stop maintaining the package um and
there's a lot of ways that you can uh
compromise a maintainer account and thus
compromise the code um so could you talk
about a couple of those techniques that
that could result in um a package
compromise it it's really funny because
one of the first technique that I've
seen uh about this was right after depy
confusion occurred uh or a bit before I
don't remember but I've seen it right
after it was Matthew Bryant uh from snap
Inc classic classic dude that that did a
research on how he managed to take over
and one of angular uh dependencies uh
through an attack that was like really
funny yeah what it did is that um you
know the the open source community and
developers really like to have custom
domains right it's cool uh to to have
like I don't know your Justin
gardner.com or r.com domain somebody's
somebody's squatting on Jus gardner.com
I I don't own that man like and they're
not even using it the last time I
checked so have you tried to send them
an email and buy it back you know maybe
someday if I'm super loaded I'll be like
hey man can I'll slide you a 20 for that
a 20 I um yeah but devs definitely love
fancy domains yeah and they swap them
pretty often with new like TLD coming
out stuff like that too exactly and so a
lot of um those domains are used for for
their main emails uh but a lot of people
forget to renew
domains and but uh what's interesting
for instance on npm is that uh even if
your domain do not exist you can still
uh log in uh just if you don't if you
have MFA you can't log in but if you
have your TFA they are not really going
to check your your domain anymore and so
a lot of maintainers in the Opus
Community do not own their domain
anymore but are still using the email as
a way to log oh my gosh dude but when I
say a lot it's a lot and there there is
a research paper uh that that that came
and I think I'm going to drop the link
so you can put that in the description
about the weak links of um supply chain
and they said that domain takeover is a
huge Wing L weak links and they did a
lot of Statistics uh on that and it was
appealing uh to to see that um and so
the the the idea behind that attack is
that your domain uh can be uh taken over
so you buy it back and uh you do a
forgot password and you can log in
again classic man Classic route the the
forgot password and and man I'm I'm
surprised that more of these um
Registries aren't enforcing TFA uh
because I feel like that's just a
no-brainer like if you are a if you're
the maintainer of a package that has
like you know X th000 installs or weekly
installs or whatever it should
absolutely be mandatory for TFA to be
enabled yeah yeah actually mpm and pip
are um starting to to do that more and
more I know that Gab is also doing that
but there is a lot of mainten that are
just setting up to MFA uh by default so
we we are on the same problem all over
again
and um but but yeah it's it's a really
interesting attack surface um and there
is like a a question when when you use
that on bbti like who is the owner of
that and that question of ownership of
the supply CH we might have need to talk
about that earlier but no no no I we got
time let's go but uh no one talks about
that yeah yeah like who HS the soft to
supply chains are the like the to the
company using the packages uh the
developers using the packages like as
end users or are the maintainers
responsible of that and like if there is
an issue who who's at fault everyone no
one and that's the problem like because
we are poting figures at one another on
that subject and no one really knows who
owns the sub chain yeah dude that's a
huge problem because it because also
like w wow yeah if I if I have the
ability to
attack a you know an asset that's in
scope in a bug bounding program a lot of
programs have these like and anything
else you can prove that we own you know
Clauses or whatever right um am I
authorized to attack that or am I not
authorized to attack that because it's
not you know even though they're running
this code is it their code no it's the
maintainer code but also is it though
you know it's like that's super tricky
yeah and even in case of a cyber attack
it's really easy for a company to say oh
no that it's not our fault it's the the
maintainer that is underpaid in a third
world country that is at fault and
you're like what the heck it's still
inside your code base you need to secure
yourself about that and that's like
really interesting because um European
regulation you know European regulations
love that uh they put an answer to that
and they said uh if you are uh targeted
in the suban attack you are responsible
because you were the one uh that pulled
the code and ultimately put that in your
code base I'm I'm clapping right now for
the people that are not on YouTube no
that that's excellent and man I I do you
know I'm American I I I'm from America
and I love America but um man uh Europe
really does have some has been doing a
great job sort of leading the way on
some of these things and there's a lot
of things that Europe messes up with
their regulations uh but uh when it
comes to making people take security
seriously it seems like they are on the
right path which is really cool I'm
going to to give some kudos to America
because they were the the first I think
that had uh s bombs so software build
materials including dependencies listing
uh
mandatory for every companies and
critical services so um having an sbom
is already already like cool step to see
to have observability on a supply chain
um but it's not enough when you know how
much attack surface there is yeah no
absolutely and I think when you build
that you know sbom as software bill of
materials yeah um it it opens your eyes
to how how many packages you're actually
relying on as well which is really cool
um I did I did want to add one thing
here I did Google it really quick
because as I was as the words were
coming out of my mouth ah npm should
enforce TFA for yeah like they did it
yeah they did it actually in 20 in 2022
actually so it's been a little while um
but it's only for packages uh with more
than 1 million weekly downloads or over
500 dependants um is what this initial
and maybe they've changed it since then
but uh this initial post from two years
ago um shows that it's that and that's
kind of a high bar I thought I thought I
thought that it was for everyone
actually okay well maybe maybe they've
they've changed it um since then but but
I'm glad to see at least they made they
made some change I know that MFA is
mandatory but maybe tofa with an
authenticator app or everything is for
more than 1 million
maybe but still really interesting that
okay all right well I I won't get too
yeah unfortunately Joel's off today so I
my I I normally I would just say Joel I
wonder about Bloody blah like and then
he would just be instantly nerd sniped
and then I would he would just research
it and then interject five minutes later
with the nuanced answer but um
unfortunately he's not here today um
he's off this week so we'll we'll leave
that to the listeners to see uh to
educate me in the YouTube comments which
will no doubt occur um so okay all right
great so that covers maintainer attacks
there's laps domains but there's also
one not that I wanted to add on
maintainers is that um from outs a u big
siiz company in France we call that next
40 companies so so the big big startups
uh they have in average between 200,000
to 400,000 packages internally uh and
I'm not talking just about like first
death packages but like with the entire
uh chain so like the entire dep right
those 400,000 packages uh has a direct
impact impact on the supply chain but
now each package is maintained between
one two to three person so you can
easily have more than one million people
uh be being able to affect your code
base and those numbers are insane
because something that that I said to a
lot of people I go in the streets I can
trust 100 people how do you trust 1
million one million maintainers dude
that is absolutely crazy
um wow dude man just hearing about the
the vastness of this it gets a little
overwhelming for me you know thank
goodness I'm not in corporate security
because like if I were a blue teamer I
just
like and even as a even as like a SAS
business owner it's like man this is
such
a it's really something you have to
allocate for cost-wise too because the
amount of resources that it takes and
and I'm sure deppy will help with this
once it you know it hits the mainstream
as well but like the amount of resources
it takes to thoroughly vet and secure
that whole flow and knowing that just
one slip up can result in compromise of
a of a buil build machine which is the
thing that has your secrets that has
like you know all of this I mean it's
just it's not it's not great dude that's
terrifying and something that like also
I've had a lot of push back with
companies when we reporting supply chain
issues they like oh but there's a low
probability of exploitation but the risk
is always remote Cod execution so how do
you assess that kind of stuff like when
you know that the risk is highly low but
when like why is the risk low the
probability of exploitation is highly
low but the risk is like the impact is
super high but how do they even factor I
mean what what do you mean the
probability of exploitation like are we
saying like this is too complicated for
attackers to figure out because we know
that that's not the case more like the
probability of a developer actually
pulling the the package because like
sometimes artifactory is really well set
up but imagine a developer forgetting to
put that npm RC file and forgets to go
through the artifactory as a company you
can't like if you have like 2,000
Developers for instance how do you know
that they are configured properly on
their machine you can't but also at the
same time they should be configured
properly so it's true that there is a
low probability that one developer may
sleep up but when they do the impact is
always
huge yeah no that's that's terrifying um
and and actually makes me think um you
know I think it would be a really cool
piece of like marketing material for you
to release that'd be really helpful for
the community to do like a a cheat sheet
for companies on like how to secure your
supply chain like go claim these package
like do you have this in your
artifactory go claim this just in case
somebody you know slips up or something
like that um because I imagine there's a
lot of sort of defense and depth
techniques that you could do that would
um prohibit some of these attacks from
happening because my my response if I'm
if I'm playing from the program side on
to what you just said is like okay well
um how do I fix that how do I fix a
developers slipping up developers always
going to slip up it's just like fishing
right well the way you fix that is you
one make sure they can't um slip up too
bad by you know claiming those packages
and to you make sure that your you know
development settings are set up with
secure defaults um but I think going
that extra layer could be really really
helpful yeah and I think that there is a
lot of like those can be fixed like uh
it's not like we are doomed and that the
world will collapse because you're are
using a supply chain uh you can fix all
those um those holes in the supply
chains and um and of course I think it
would be great resource to provide uh
guidance on how to fix these issues and
also how to assess them but it has been
a really long debate with a lot of
different programs on how to assess in
the B Ram and paradig supply chain
issues because again we don't have a
scope anymore but the impact is always
great so how did you assess that dude
it's got to be it's got to be impact
based man I mean at the end of the day
you've gota you've got to look at these
scenarios and you've got to say okay
listen I if if you know Lupin is
attacking this you know oneoff little
little Dev you know environment over
here but then it's compromising a server
that has access to these AWS keys that
give you the ability to interact with
and like I mean that's the end of the
freaking world you know like the Keys of
the Kingdom yeah exactly and it and and
we know that it happens all too often
and that's and I think I think from the
bug Bounty side obviously doing your
your due diligence and really
understanding what an attacker could do
from from that perspective takes time
and takes effort but I think that's
where you sort kind of separate the
wheat from the chaff there as far as
programs goes you separate the good
programs from the bad programs and ones
that are really um and not necessarily
the bad programs you know I I should be
a little bit more understanding uh if
there's anything these uh you know
program versus hacker debates uh that
we've had in the PO over the past couple
months has taught me it's like you know
a lot of these people are severely
understaffed these organizations are
severely understaffed and uh just cannot
get the amount of people that they need
to do their job properly of course that
that's why I'm bringing those debates on
on the table because as a Bug Hunter I
want to be paid uh but I need also to
understand the real and um and that's a
way in bu buti to re do more bones and
get more rewards is by understanding
what the program needs from you for
instance the email take over to domains
some programs accept that uh it's rare
but uh it really depends on their
maturity but a lot of programs will tell
you it's not our responsibility uh the
dev like it's the maintainer fault and I
I mean in some ways they're right like
they're not going to claim domains that
are not theirs right uh but at the same
time it will impact the supply chain uh
at one point so it all boys down to your
maturity your budget and uh how you want
to treat the the research Community more
than bug Hunters is really more about
the research and like Noel techniques
and how do you see them and appreciate
them uh inside your bug program I I
think if it if it expands your
understanding of your own infrastructure
and it you make remediations based off
of that I think you should pay for the
scenario the worst case scenario if you
do not have the the resources to do your
full due diligence and and I think
that's painful for a lot of um a lot of
bug Bounty programs um but at the end of
the day we all know what should be
happening which is that you should be
doing a a thorough assessment of these
threats and then if but if you don't
have the Manpower and the Staffing to do
it you know maybe split the difference
with the researcher at least but don't
categorize these as lows or mediums
because their the the impact is really
is really large and and we all know
anybody who's ever performed an external
to internal pen test knows that once you
get in like your job gets a million
times easier um so yeah I guess we'll
we'll leave that at that okay so
maintainers they're massive they're
everywhere there's millions of them that
can commit into your project at any
given time love that for us um and uh
but there's also multiple ways to attack
the maintainers there can be you know
them letting their domains lapse like we
like we mentioned but there can also be
weak credential attacks on these
maintainers and there could also be um
these maintainers leaking their own
personal secrets um in into uh from
other side projects or something like
that and then giving an attacker access
to their like GitHub account or their um
you know registry account and allowing
the attacker to move from there um so is
that something you're also you know
you've also seen and something you're
scanning for with in deppy yeah uh we
are still in a research module right now
so we have this beta we call the
Frontline access uh that that will not
have those secret scanning but we we are
researching more and more trying to
remove all those false positives but
definitely uh something really
interesting uh to see
because like even in the CI compromis
realm uh there is a lot of developers
that set up their own cic pipeline that
will use their npm token that is tied uh
to to their entire organization or their
company and if they don't secure their
their pipeline you are going to
compromise the overall uh company so
once you manage to find a package then
you need to find the GitHub Associated
to the package with the pipeline or the
gitlab then once you find that you need
to find all the maintainers that can
commit code inside once you find those
maintainers you find all their projects
all their pipelines and you scan back
again oh my gosh and that's something
that we want to do and uh that that we
are actually starting to to do but that
spidering is like how much in depth we
go that's the question I I imagine
that's actually pretty computationally
expensive too like when we're talking
about the network effect of all this
like like you know you've got all of
these maintainers let's say there's a
million maintainers and then each of
them has you know 100 repos or whatever
and and then each of these repos have
like years of git history right and it's
like wow now we're having to sift
through like terabytes of code to try to
find that one place where some developer
you know put a token put a token or
committed an SSH key or something like
that of course um we we we have some
technical challenges here and uh we have
a lot of fun with them there is a lot of
stuff that we thought that that were
impossible for instance related to dep
because uh by the end of the day we
we're like it's
exponential uh and uh and we have a lot
of computing problem but uh through
different uh techniques we managed to uh
make one request that were taking like
three minutes to analyze per package we
managed to make it like five seconds oh
wow okay wow five second optimization
going into this yeah it's already long
though but uh we're getting there
and you're writing this in Rust too
right so this is not like you're all of
this is what yeah yeah definitely yeah
yeah and it's not like all of this is
running in like python or like you know
some some much slower language you're
trying to do this at a really optimized
level and I think that's the right the
right choice from the beginning now
hearing about the scale and I we had a
little bit of a debate on this the last
time we discussed your we did like a
little brainstorming um you know meeting
for your product and I was like man like
why you got to write this in Rust but
now that I'm sort of understanding the
the the breadth of all of this
um it's an abely
massive um that makes a lot of sense
okay so the maintainer attacks we've got
those um now this is
a I guess this is sort of a complicated
question so people that are trying to
build out these software build materials
right this this list of dependencies
that they have for their given software
I was thinking like okay wow this is
actually going to be really tricky like
we got to kind of nuanced you know map
out everything else yeah but then I
realized all we have to do is clone it
down and then just run mpm install right
like yeah I mean that will pull that's
why these node modules uh folders are
just so like ridiculously massive is
they pull everything down right so I
mean is is a good way to do this to
actually just clone the repo do npm
install and then just like find you know
find Dot and just look at all of the
packages yeah I I think uh this
technique is not as scalable because
when you have a repository that is two
gigs and then you you see all the the
thees it becomes horrible uh but um you
can optimize a lot of things for
instance GitHub expose an API for the
sbom so every really oh that's awesome
yeah every public uh uh GitHub
repository as an sbom Associated and
that you can call with an API no way
yeah and if there is I did not know that
and if there is a lock file uh you can
actually have all the the packages back
dude this is so this is so cool yeah I
really appreciate I did not know that
this existed this is really cool this is
not like a secret source of our scanning
but um really helped me a lot uh when I
was building all the tools um yeah I
think that that would be the best way um
to well especially for us you know for
for for people looking for the you know
8020 situation here um that's really
cool and and I think stuff like like me
not knowing about that shows you know
how
how all there are all these little
pockets of of info that we kind of need
to be able to address the supply chain
thing um correctly but I'm really glad
that GitHub went ahead and and went
after that because uh that's a great
level to solve it at right any almost
everything ends up in a GitHub repo at
some point and so um and I imagine
gitlab will put something together or
already has
something already is doing the something
and they also have artifact toies per
reposit
so one repository can expose one
artifactory that is just for the
repository oh wow yeah it's really
interesting and since gitlab is open
source you can see how they are pulling
packages and stuff like that and there
is a lot of weird thing that they are
doing and it's so fun to see the
shortcut that artifact toies are taking
to be compliant with the protocol of mpm
and stuff like that and like most of the
calls are mocked which is so funny oh
man
H I I I imagine that's a whole a whole
you know good scope for you to go after
when when looking at at these um you
know GitHub Enterprise in in gitlab as
well we can talk about that a little bit
but um if you really want to find that
20% I think more than checking the
dependencies uh go check the artif
factories but because they all have a
buben program and once you find artif
factories uh there is so many bugs why
because so is infinitely complex and so
there is so many use cases even within
an organization like one developer can a
developer remove a version no on the npm
registry it's not allowed but on
artifactory it's allowed and you don't
have any logging in monitoring uh so you
can replace a version backdoing the
version that already exists wow but and
you don't have any way to know which
developer did that uh that's a problem
and once you you step back and you do
not see that as a web app scope but more
about a supply chain Hub uh you'll find
many more vulnerabilities that you may
think is a low vulnerability from a
business perspective but always ends up
in a remote code execution and so yeah
the stakes here are very high yeah I I
I've been hacking artif factories for
the past year I I think and uh the
attack surface is so big for one single
endpoint because of all the supply chain
implication so you have one endpoint
just the one pulling the packages and
you can hack it in so many different
ways because for instance they didn't
think about uh ranges versions uh or
they they didn't think about a lower
case or uppercase or unicodes and so you
have like confusion here which is so
funny to see yeah dude normalization
bugs just all sorts of all sorts of
craziness I imagine you know one one
layer of URL encoding Miss you know
across this whole thing could could mess
up a bunch of stuff too and because
those are proxies artifactors are
proxies you also have ssrf in some ways
yeah wow that's that's nuts man there's
so many so many ways to look at that
problem um okay so sub dependency
mapping we got the software build
materials we got our npm install that
sort of thing um so the next area that I
sort of wanted to go to was this and we
kind of touched on this already but
attacking the artif factories and
Registries right there's a great way to
go after that like you mentioned is
doing a source code analysis of the
artif factories they've got bu Bounty
programs going after the way that they
deal with this but also it's possible
for us to attack the Registries um and
and so I know you have a bug here that
you are going to share with npm which I
think would be really really cool and it
just went out uh I it just went out like
right before we recorded podast that's
awesome that's great and and so um we'll
be covering it right on the Pod just a
couple days we'll be releasing this pod
later this week so um you know we should
be a pretty fresh coverage on this but
um talk about your experience hacking on
these Registries themselves and and what
kind of impact uh and what kind of
attack vectors they have yeah uh so uh
the B that we we disclosed today was on
npm uh npm is owned by gab I know that a
lot of developers OR tech people do not
know that uh but npm by the end of the
day is Microsoft in some
ways uh oh my gosh yeah multiple layers
of acquisition there okay yeah exactly
and so
um we were doing like a a subm module
for dep again in research mode and and
our question was like how we can uh you
know impact the availability of the
packages of our clients and because they
have like artifactory were like hey what
if we do cash poisoning on the
artifactory we denied the artifactory if
they are public and we just you know
does all the the pipelines of our
clients that will be a really fun
right yeah that would be nuts actually
and I love that you went for
availability as well that you didn't
forget about the A and the CIA Triad
because um you know it it makes a lot of
sense to go after confidentiality
getting access to that source code
Integrity obviously has RCU based
impacts but availability I think would
not be one of the things that would pop
into my head immediately when I'm
thinking about this but it has such a
massive impact on the scope because it
breaks all these builds um definitely
and and cash poisoning is the perfect
attack for this because um you know they
have if these packages are being
downloaded millions and millions and
millions of times they have to be cashed
or else the the CPU load is going to be
way too much um so tell me tell me how
you ended up being able to exploit that
yeah so we developed a small script
integrated that to to depi and uh we
forgot to remove the public Registries
uh and so we did the first scan and then
result uh registry. npmjs.com
no that's no no I'm not trusting my
script that was the first run and I'm
not kidding like this is twice in in our
research where we had like a first hit
uh so a lot of dude Miracles are
happening man like seriously like one
the script works the first time you run
it two it works on the freaking biggest
registry out there and so I thought it
was a false positive right and I I go to
check manually and it triggers we have a
cash poisoning if you set a a header at
the moment you do the get request uh to
to to to take the package uh it will
create a 44 and this 44 will be cashed
on the like the prod
registry and like it's not even Atif
Factory it's it's like the registry
right and um and so you must have been
so freaked out when it worked you're
you're like I can't I can't believe this
man so I I didn't write that in the
article but I every step back from the
computer closed everything and just went
in my bed and just you know stared at
the ceiling for a little while yeah
exactly I was like funny no I it's not
possible I always you know we talk about
uh finding bugs and stuff like that on
the Pod and and one of the one of the
things I always do that I've mentioned a
couple times is soon as I find a bug
just step back a little bit take a
breath and then run to my wife as fast
as I can say look what I just found this
amazing thing and it's like no I haven't
reported it yet no I I have I haven't
double checked it yet even you know and
then you know half the time it's like a
false positive and and she's like having
to pull me out of the the pit of despair
or whatever after I thought I had a mega
crit and now it's not but I actually do
that with a lot of bug Hunters friends
where I you know I've sent to you some
of those crazy oh my gosh I love those
moments man dude I found that and like
oh no no it was aot yeah I I love your I
love your
um I love your messages I found it it's
crazy
it's uh wait a second but wait maybe
it'll no no that's not going to work you
know it's the life of a bug Hunter man
the life of a buck yeah but but when we
hit something we are really happy we are
we are and it shows the passion for it
so um it keeps us coming back for more
yeah but but but here I was a little bit
more freaked out because I knew the
implication of a software software
supply chain bug at that scale like if
you manage to deny a a package you can
like basically impact the entire
JavaScript EOS system and yeah bring
down pipelines uh and developers machine
and like just say hey tomorrow is a hly
day for everyone right you're not
developing
anymore oh my gosh dude can you imagine
the Havoc that would cause if you like
dust like Express or something like that
on like a Friday night or something or
like when did people deploy probably
Thursday you know dos dos Express on
Thursday that'd be terrible man that
would be so funny I think and a lot of
like death team security team and
incident response would be like what the
heck is happening yeah yeah all of a
sudden this package just Express just
404s on on npm it's like we know the way
they think an incident response is like
oh we did something wrong and then you
check and then you're like oh no they
did something wrong like wait a minute
how' that happen it was DNS
they did something wrong yeah I was
thinking about the Facebook bgp bug like
everyone was freaking out like oh my DNS
is not working it's like oh it's
Facebook no worries man and there's
that's another interesting area there is
if you could attack it at the DNS level
as well I imagine things would be cashed
but that that's an interesting approach
let's write that down try it and then we
do a pod again might have to bleep that
who knows whatever yeah um uh so the
other the other sort of um attack factor
that I had and dos makes a bunch of
sense here but also if there was an idor
in this sort of environment it would
absolutely be terrible um have you done
any of that more granular testing on
these on these uh organizations or
mostly are you focusing on the bigger
ecosystem yeah for now I've done it on
the artif factories uh level uh and not
on the registry uh because like I've
sent uh this bug uh for for GitHub npm
and uh they give me a $500 br
for like the do oh my gosh dude yeah and
I was like really surprised because uh
they said oh no it's a distributed den
of service and I'm like I managed to
reproduce it from a machine of course
the caching wasn't like for every back
ends but you know you you were still
affecting a huge part of the the traffic
if you managed to to exploit it
correctly and they said no it's a DS so
it's not uh in our scope of the program
it's more abuse and I was like oh my
gosh dude yeah I mean you've got a
you've got a uh a screenshot right here
in your blog post that like says npm
install and then you're downloading the
the the package yeah and then you know
you can see it goes through successfully
and then just like what what is this
like one minute later not even one
minute later you you try to reinstall it
again and it and it says no there's a
404 not found like how could they how
could they argue with that I mean uh I I
I didn't understand and I've wrote in
the blog U my you know why I was
bothered about this entire assessment I
have nothing against get up security
team they are amazing people again I
will tell you again that they are very
amazing people but the overall
assessment of this report was um a bit
of a mess I would say yeah agree and I I
I don't know if you've seen the timeline
but um what they did is that uh they
said it was an internal duplicate at the
beginning uh and then uh a couple of
months later they traed it uh and then a
couple of months later they closed it as
informative uh six months later I sent
the Ronnie I'm so sorry man I know you
told me lately you're a little burnout
on bug bounties but and it don't makes
total sense given this experience
because this is not how it's supposed to
work when you're doing supply chain uh
it have it happens a lot uh that kind of
assessment uh but um yeah I and then six
months later I think I sent like hey can
we disclose the varability they said oh
yeah and we can help for the technical
analysis of your WR up and I was like
awesome but it didn't fix the vity right
they didn't fix it and they told me we
are allowing the disclosure no and so I
sent them the draft report and they told
me hey we're fixing the vulnerability
now yeah of course I imagine so but but
my my goal was disclosure wasn't like to
pressure or anything I just wanted to
talk about like a super cability that I
really loved uh but I was really
disappointed about the assessment and
the fact that you know one year later
one year after reporting that fixing the
avilability is for me like really weird
yeah it's super weird especially when
the impact is so is so wide and I I'm
looking through here and I think they
mention in here that like there was some
um inconsistency with the caching
servers it seems like where like uh only
yeah every every fourth or fifth request
was being dropped but I'm like when it's
Express that you can you know like one
you know every fourth or fifth request
is like millions of requests like why is
this a problem to put some numbers
Express is 30 Millions install per week
uh and on the LA latest version it's 12
Millions install so every time there is
a latest version in one week it it'ss 12
million
installs and and so even though you have
one4 of the requests uh that that are
getting denied 1/4 of the 12 Millions is
that's insane dude yeah that man this is
this I mean like you said I I love the
GitHub team too there has been
some difficulties with them in the past
just to be perfectly clear and in my
experience they've they've come around
on it and they normally um you know
after you have to talk to them and you
you know go through the whole impact
scenario they've paid out really really
generously for me in the past but I
imagine you know sometimes it doesn't
always end up quite that way but I hope
after this article is released and the
the General Security you know industry
says oh [__] you know this is bad um
that exactly that you know they come
back and make it right on this because
uh this is a serious V man again I my
goal is not to put pressure with the
disclosure like if people wants to to
say something publicly they they they
will tell something publicly it's not my
my problem like I really wanted to talk
about the research and more like hey on
on depi we have a subm module that will
check for
a2o uh which was like the the the main
goal of uh This research to be able to
demonstrate that a supply chain attacks
when it comes to AV abity impact can be
huge yeah yeah clearly no that that's
that's
amazing um all right so we've covered
attacks on the artifact Ries and on the
Registries maintainer attacks the last
one we sort of alluded to CI related
bugs um there's there's some research
out there you guys can go and uh and
dive into by Ed overflow and this guy
named Justin
Gardner never heard of him yeah yeah um
so there's that and there's also um I
guess we will touch on one of these
because I I also wanted to mention this
um last time or last time we had Johan
on on the Pod he he mentioned this whole
concept of hijacking a a flow uh a CI
flow um inside of gitlab and I think
that that's a really interesting
approach and there's lots of ways to do
that uh but I think that's another
really um important part of this whole
um supply chain attack Vector concept
yeah um because these things are getting
more and more complex as as they go and
uh and there's more and more
opportunities for for people to inject
their their input into it whether it be
a pull request whether it be like a
lapsed domain or S3 bucket or that sort
of thing um and then gain control of
these CI flows and then leak important
secrets and that sort of thing um so so
yeah what are your thoughts on that
whole on that whole front and how is
deppy addressing this issue it's
amazing I I I I love this area of
research uh there is one researcher that
have been doing a lot of work on that
and his name is Adan and uh it's amazing
to see all of is a c bug and I'm really
impressed by how many uh bugs we can
find in this attack surface and again
it's one functionality but the attack
surface is huge and definitely uh
something on on the road map of D for
now we're focusing on software artifact
but builds as we said since the
beginning is an important component of
the software supply chain and is the
natural uh process to go through builds
at one point with dep uh we found a
couple of vulnerabilities real related
to C but more like GitHub uh
overall yeah yeah there there's lots of
overlap there because I mean at the end
of the day the stuff is going to be
present in in GitHub because that's
where the the CI is running from so if
you're just doing this you know if
you're assessing from a GitHub level you
can see a lot of that and I think the
only exception to that really is like
the the stuff that's being injected
directly um at the CI level you know the
the the tokens and the API keys and that
sort of thing um and then also
the logs that are generated from the uh
the the CI themselves and and that's
where you know that research that we did
with Trav CI came in and and where I
found an rce a while back it was
actually one one of my first rc was um
grepping through uh logs for this uh
crypto website on their CI um and
finding out that they had echoed out
their private key in one uh commit and I
just used that private key to just log
in as route to the server and uh and it
should have been a 10K Bounty but it was
like they're like um it's a 1K Bounty by
you know classic classic crypto program
uh BS but yeah I feel like it there's
definitely some difficulties in in the
sort
of supply chain bug Bounty ecosystem on
getting them to actually pay the
vulnerabilities some for some reason
well one te think that I really like um
for now I'm not focusing on um exploting
the CI but more about the results of the
and one technique that I I love is that
to find all the metadata around the
pulling of the packages so you are going
to see the the traffic of the which
artifactory they they use and so and
sometimes you can also find it in inside
the JavaScript exposed uh publicly like
which artifactory they're using so
basically what I do is that I copy the
domain of U of this private artifactory
that we can find an inci uh and we can
find in public JavaScript usually if I
find it in in inci it's because SN LAX
gave me the CI he's an amazing Hunter uh
and really good with CI too so often he
G me the thefactory but then I go on
giab and put path uh colon um and then
package-lock dojason and then I put the
artifactory domain
because what's happening in the lock
file you see all the all the the
artifact and where is the
tjz ball like the T right and so you see
the domain and so every lock file you
know it comes from a developer of the
organization and that's where I'm
managed to leak source code of like
private source code not even packages
right source code of uh of many
organization and de on developers uh
accounts that weren't even inside the
organization it's just like their like
test account and they did a a a pushed
internal source code and there you manag
to find a lot of different stuff
credentials um you can access like do
code review you can already reported for
some company it's already good enough to
to report that kind of bugs um um and so
that's like my technique to uh find
expose the source code go through the
factory and the build results that's
that's an awesome tip and and I think
also getting your hands on any sort of
Enterprise source code is just so nuts
like I I remember that that initial
dependency confusion blog post you know
mentioned that we were that I handed him
some source code from from PayPal the
source code that we found that was
actively being used in PayPal's
environment leaked secrets in it that we
were able to use to encrypt and decrypt
stuff um and it led to like over 50k in
Bucks uh just from being able to see
these little pieces of middleware here
and there that were like popping up
around that's huge um and it's like wow
just getting your hands on any any piece
of that that's actually running allows
you to make such more nuanced attack
factors um towards that Target so really
really essential that can be taken more
Broad in the supply chain and you just
um check all the the the internal
domains of a company and then you search
them on GitHub uh and uh that could be
also a really fun uh thing to do yeah
yeah I think I think that's really um
anytime you
see here's here's the secret sauce for
how we did it with with PayPal actually
it's been years I'll just kind of um you
know uh share the secrets sauce here um
essentially you know in in PayPal's
environment there's a a bunch of
different little microservices right
that that uh are powering the P PayPal
app and each there's a way I I won't
disclose it all but there's a way that
you'll see these around you know in the
in the responses of the requests or when
errors are triggered or whatever um and
then you can take these little
microservices names and you just put
those bad boys into
GitHub and and and you know any time and
those microservice names correlate to
like package is for the code and so you
put them into GitHub and then you you
know search around look through
everything and uh you know you may if
you get lucky um uh pop some some
internal source code uh and and I think
a lot of other companies have similar
structures uh I'm not sure if those
little package names or host names or
microservice names are getting leaked as
much but I imagine I know on the back
end that they have similar structures to
that so um anytime you see a unique
string that seems to correlate to the
infrastructure behind the application
you're attacking always take that to
GitHub and and Run a search on it
because um you'd be super surprised on
what kind of stuff pop definitely um all
right dude let's see uh okay so the npm
cash poisoning bug super cool the tldr
of that one was that you were able to go
to attack the npm registry where they're
actually downloading the package files
directly and uh you know we won't
specify through what method but you're
able to somehow provide a uh a um
additional piece of information in that
request that makes it go to a 404 and
that 404 gets cached and then when
anyone else tries to request that page
again uh they get the 404 instead of
access to that you know tar file or
whatever it is um crazy bug I really
hope that gets addressed and we don't
have to deal with that in the ecosystem
um let's talk about the next one that
you wanted to share on the pod which is
the grafana npx uh confusion yeah oh
that's uh that was uh really funny uh so
first of all I think uh this this needs
to be said uh the graph security team is
one of the most mature security team
I've ever work worked with and not just
they mature they're wholesome they are
so funny to work with and uh it has been
a pleasure uh to send them a bug yeah I
had the same experience with them back
in in 2020 with the graffan ssrf they
were they were awesome and so uh what
happened is that I was again dep
research mode uh and this time I wanted
to find a bug on GID laab cutu uh
because I have a friend that challenged
me to do so and uh and I was like okay
let's do it but when I analyzing um
gitlab I managed to find like a
dependency uh that is called graph Das
toolkit um that was uh not claimed uh
public and uh this boyss down to
um um basically gra2 is not a package
it's a binary but there is a package
manager called npx uh which is from and
the same npm team and NP extends from uh
nod package
execute and instead of uh of being a
manager and trying to install packages
I've seen this okay I know what you're
talking about instead of being uh a
manager that uh will just install the
package it will run a binary directly
okay so these are like for like command
line applications or whatever that
you're going to use to supplement some
you know maybe use grafana toolkit or
whatever to add a user to graa or
something like that from the command
line or something yeah exactly and so uh
what's interesting when npx is that uh
if you do npx a package and you do not
have the binary name inside your
computer it will pull from the public
registry and then uh just install the
package and we'll run it so you don't do
not have to do an npm install command uh
before but there is a problem it's the
npx takes a binary name but the public
registry is packages name so there is a
confusion on npx side between both of
them
basically if you have like graph Dash
toolkit was like the name of the binary
but the name of the package was grafana
tokit a and so a lot a lot of companies
in their uh docu file
cicd uh or even documentation uh was
writing npx grafana Das toolkit but this
package didn't exist so what I did I
claimed it and every time that you do
npx D toolkit you download my package I
claimed it yeah that's great I love it
and and you you are uh basically uh
downloading uh this binary that I've
claimed on
npm uh what's really interesting uh from
from this bug and that we need to say
from Graf team it didn't affect their
source code and actually all their cicd
that were using npx gra toolkit because
there were some were archived from a
long time ago but the open source
committee was still using uh these
command because they usually install the
package first and then running the npx
command sure but if you do not have the
binary installed and that can go really
fast uh then you have the same
dependency confusion and you have a
remal execution but what's interesting
here it's not on the artifactory level
anymore it's directly on the package
manager and that's a realm of research
that we haven't seen much before ah okay
at the at the I see yeah we are not
trying to impact the artifact and confus
Factory we are trying to confuse uh the
package manager and the CLE to install
the packages and so that's an area of
research of depi that we are doing a lot
trying to find those zero days of
misconfiguration there's so many to of
these package managers there's you know
npm yarn just goes on and on and on UMES
so wow yeah there's a lot of attack
surface there well I am super looking
forward to uh seeing the results of your
research research on this stuff with Dey
lopin it seems like you're doing an
excellent job and I you know it's pretty
great that I haven't seen any other
major competitors doing what you're
doing here um so it it's cool to see you
sort of leading the the charge with this
and I think uh it's also great to have
you as a bug Bounty Hunter because we
get the the sort of from an experienced
bug Bounty Hunter perspective of how we
can apply this sort of supply chain
vulnerabilities to bug Bounty so um
thanks for coming on the pot and talking
about that yeah EX for the the
invitation uh it's always super great to
to talk with you indeed indeed thanks so
much man um anything else you want to
shout obviously we've got deppy that's
at what is it
lnhh do and Tech uh yes lnh h.
teppy you can find more information
about the tool there yeah um anything
else you want to shout before we end the
Pod yeah I really want to shout out uh
to the entire French team in the Haan
World Cup uh get out of here no cut it
cut it cut it off I I just want to say
those are crazy people finding crazy
vulnerabilities and uh amazing talents
amazing young people new in the field
and just breaking the biggest companies
in the world so I'm just impressed and
amazingly surprised by all the talents
that we have in France uh and yeah VI La
France oh my gosh all right let's go cut
the Pod here let's let's
go and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack along alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there